Jeffrey Bergier

- **(949) 287-1699**
- jeffburg (at) jeffburg (dot) com
- www.jeffburg.com
- Inner Richmond, San Francisco

TL;DR

UX Interaction Designer - 4 years

I studied Industrial Design, which focuses on the physical. However, the part of Industrial Design that appeals to me most is problem solving and design thinking. These skills are incredibly beneficial in not just Industrial Design but in all design fields. For the past 4 years I have been designing complex workflows for enterprise networking products.

iOS Developer - 3 years, part-time

I learned Objective-C a few months before Swift was announced. I love both languages, but I love Swift just a little bit more. I enjoy making beautiful user interfaces with UIKit (iOS) and AppKit (macOS). I also enjoy making clean code that is easy to read and easy to change. I particularly like controlling the size of my UIViewController subclasses.

Tools

★ Expert

- Sketch
- Balsamiq
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop

☆ Advanced

- Xcode
- Swift
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe flash

Proficient

- Objective-C
- Adobe Fireworks
- Microsoft Office

♥ Hobby

- HTML/CSSMac OS X Server
- Microcontrollers

Experience

User Experience Designer, Riverbed Technology, San Francisco January 2013 - Present

When I started at Riverbed, there was no UX team at all. My coworker and I crept our way into every part of the engineering organization and proved the value of UX to the company. Since then, an entire UX team has formed with a Directory of UX, a user research, a visual designer, and an interaction designer (me). We all work directly with engineers and product managers to solve problems.

At Riverbed, our customers have huge networks. Many of our customers have over 1000 Riverbed appliances distributed all over the world. My work for the past 2 years has been to make deploying, configuring, troubleshooting and upgrading Riverbed Appliances easy. Because our customers have so many appliances each, the real challenge at Riverbed is making it easy to do all of those operations in bulk.

Teacher, General Assembly, San Francisco

December 2015 - Present

I lead a monthly iOS Development 101 workshop at General Assembly. Students range from no programming experience to experienced Java/C#/C++ developers. This can make it hard to keep everyone up to speed without others being bored. I developed the 3 hour curriculum with this in mind. The workshops are an incredible amount of fun and a great lerning experience for all involved.

Volunteer Organizer & Teacher, MobileBridge, San Francisco

March 2014 - Present

MobileBridge / Bridge Foundry is an organization that helps organizers put on free workshops to teach Technologies to people who are under-represented in technology.

I enjoy developing the iOS curriculum, helping to organize workshops, and especially teaching for MobileBridge / Bridge Foundry. Because we focus on empowering underserved communities in tech, the students are always eager and wanting to learn. Working with the entire Bridge Foundry community has been an incredibly rewarding experience.

User Experience Designer, Woopra, Inc., San Francisco

January 2012 - January 2013

Fast paced UX work in a small startup environment. In addition to design responsibilities, I also handled support tickets, bug reports, and other office management duties. My work involved direct interaction with front-end and backend engineers, marketing and sales people as well as the company's founder, to make sure user needs were properly addressed.

Organizer / Teacher, Industrial Design Outreach, San Francisco 2011 – 2012 Graphic Design Intern, Sugar Publishing, San Francisco – 2010 – 2011 Technician Trainer, MacMEDIC, San Francisco – 2010 – 2011 Genius, Apple Store, Burlingame, California – 2007 – 2009 Store Manager, Sunglass Hut, San Francisco – 2006 – 2007

Education

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Design

San Francisco State University

Industrial Design, San Francisco State University

Fall 2008 - Spring 2011

Product Design, Brunel University, London

Autumn 2009 - Spring 2010